Aldo Munaretto

Calle Sorzano, 16. 28043 Madrid. Spain E-mail: <u>aldomunaretto@gmail.com</u>
Mobile: (+34)635096305

Personal Statement

I am a comprehensive professional with a bachelor's degree in Chemistry with 9+ years of experience in the commercial world, oriented to the achievement of objectives and to establish long-term commercial relations. The diversity in the portfolio of products and clients served, has given me versatility that allows me to adapt to the needs of the situation to face. I have analytical skills and the ability to solve problems, even under pressure. Excellent interpersonal relationships, responsible, dynamic and proactive. I have the ability to work in teams both inside and outside the office. Always willing to learn new things and to fulfill my goals in the personal and work.

Working Experience

Distribuciones Industriales y Científicas SL. * February 2017 – currently * Madrid, Spain *Commercial Delegate*

- Commercial Delegate of scientific and laboratory material
 - Manage the needs of the company's customers regarding chemical and microbiological reagents; instrumentation and scientific equipment; laboratory furniture and equipment; products for the fields of: molecular biology, pathological anatomy and phytopathology.
 - o Prospection and increasing of the client portfolio.
 - o Analysis of the competition and customer loyalty.
 - o Implementation of the business plan of the company.
 - o Planning and execution of offline / online marketing campaigns.

Piélagos Comunicaciones S.L. * April 2016 – December 2016 * Madrid, Spain *Commercial Advisor*

- Commercial Advisor in Telecommunications
 - o Commercial of physical and virtual PBXs for business telecommunications.
 - Cross selling of other products and services offered by the company (video surveillance cameras, biometric access controls, etc.).
 - o Loyalty and maintenance of the client portfolio.

Grupo CMC * August 2015 – October 2015 * Madrid, Spain *Telemarketer*

- Telemarketer in Call Center for Clients of Ono's portfolio.
 - o Commercial in the service Click to Call for Vodafone TV campaign (soccer package).
 - o Cross selling of other products and services offered by Vodafone.

Securitas Direct S.A.U. * April 2015 – August 2015 * Madrid, Spain **Security Expert – Senior**

- Door to door salesman and installer of Verisure alarm systems.
 - Explain and demonstrate the functions of the equipment offered by the company, focusing on customer needs and competitive differences with the competition.
 - o Installation of the equipment.

Corporación Technipore, S.A. * April 2008 - May 2015 * Valencia, Venezuela Account Executive

- Venezuelan Central Region Sales Executive for Corporación Technipore, S.A. distributor and dealer partner of Merck Millipore, Beckman Coulter, Hygiena, Formulaction, Ocean Optics & others; see: http://www.technipore.com.ve.
 - Sale of polymer filtration membranes and laboratory equipment for pharmaceutical industries, food and beverage industries, universities and research institutes.
 - Be involved in direct filtration and downstream process filter selection and sizing, process optimization and process validation activities associated with biopharmaceutical and water treatment processes.
 - Perform in-house and on-site bench-scale experimental work such as sterile membrane filtration, depth filtration and tangential flow filtration trials.
 - Collaborate with and provide technical support to customer process development groups.
 - Increase the number of accounts on the company.
- Chemistry- related technical support for use of the products we sell.
- Areas of Knowledge Involved: Industrial Filtration (Water & Products), Membrane Filtration Microbiology, Particle Characterization, Process Monitoring.
- Industries Involved: Pharmaceutical, Veterinarian, Food & Beverages, Petrochemical, Universities and Research Institutes.

Windar Inc. * August 2003-March 2007 * Winter Springs FL, USA Co-Founder & COO

 Company dedicated to import and distribute wines in the State of Florida from suppliers: Azienda Vinicola Dal Maso (Montebello - VI) and Cantine Lenotti (Bardolino - VR). Responsible for the operations of wine's nationalization, as well as the interaction with customers.

Extra-Academic Formation

Grupo de Apoyo para el Desarrollo Estudiantil – Supporting Group for Students' Development – *GADE (Universidad Simón Bolívar)*: courses on personal communication, leadership, group management, cooperation and team work. Work as a volunteer in the reception of new students in the university and later advise them in their first years of study.

Volunteering

FEDECAMARAS Carabobo - Federation of Chambers and Associations of Commerce and Production in Venezuela sectional Carabobo (October 25-28, 2000): Responsible for logistics and relationship with sponsors in the National Assembly of Regionals FEDECAMARAS 2000.

Education

2004	B.S. in Chemistry	Universidad Simón Bolívar
2018	Master in Business Intelligence	Caracas, Venezuela Universitat de Barcelona
2010	Waster in Business Intelligence	Barcelona, Spain

Skills

- Commercial awareness.
- Negotiation and persuasion.
- Problem solving.
- Proactive.
- Organized.
- Self-motivated.
- Languages: Spanish, English (Computer Based TOEFL: 253 / Jan 2004) and notions of Italian & German.
- Proficient in the use of Microsoft Windows, MacOS, Linux and Microsoft Office.